

HERSANN FONSECA QUIRÓS

COMPUTER SYSTEM ENGINEER

Computer Systems Engineer with almost 6 years working in different areas of technology. In addition, I have experience in software testing and quality control. Experienced in all phases of Software testing life defect cycle, including testing, tracking, management, and reporting.

Understanding of existing QA best practices and methodologies to design, implement and automate processes. Experience with QA Automation.

I have strong communication & interpersonal skills. I like to work in a collaborative, innovative, flexible and team-oriented environment.

CONTACT



+506 8315-4829



hfonseca_07@hotmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/hfonsecaguiros



https://hersannfonsecaquiros.github.io/





WORK HISTORY

2016 - ACTUALLY **QA1 ENGINEER**

MOBILIZE.NET - San José, Costa Rica

Execution of manual and automated test plans, functional, integration, regression and performance testing and frameworks for responsive web and desktop applications. Documentation of software bugs with detailed steps for replication of the defects found. All tracking of the Test cases and bugs using

Creation of automated test plans using Selenium or WebDriver (programming in Java and C#). Creation and execution of automated performance test plans using JMeter, Jenkins, BlazeMeter and HP Load Runner Suite with the following objective: to find bottlenecks, transactions with high load times, etc.

2014 - ACTUALLY

OWN BUSINESS - Heredia, Costa Rica

APLICACTION DEVELOPER Development of desktop applications for commercial buildings. The applications were developed in Visual Basic .NET (Win Forms), SQL Server 2014, Crystal Reports. Also, using 3-layer architecture.

2013 - 2016

UNIVERSIDAD LATINA - Heredia, Costa Rica

ASSISTANT IN TECHNICAL SUPPORT

I had the obligation to ensure the proper functioning of the equipment in classrooms, laboratories and administrative bodies of the university. Excellent skills in configuration of different operating systems and applications.



EDUCATION

2018 – IN PROGRESS	MAJORING IN COMPUTER PROJECT MANAGEMENT
	UNIVERSIDAD LATINA – Heredia, Costa Rica
2016	BACHELOR DEGREE IN COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING UNIVERSIDAD LATINA – Heredia, Costa Rica
2012	TECHNICAL IN MAINTENANCE AND REPARATION OF COMPUTERS INSTITUTO PARAUNIVERSITARIO JIMÉNEZ
2011	BACHELOR DEGREE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION





Languages

English (Intermediate), Spanish.

Programming Languages

VB.NET (Windows Forms), C#, JAVA, C++, PHP, CSS, HTML, SQL.

Others

Knowledge of Windows and Linux operating system architecture, configuration and administration. Experience with the following tools: Selenium, JMeter -Taurus - Jenkins - BlazeMeter, HP Load Runner Suite, Team Foundation Server (TFS), Virtual Box, VMWare, Source Tree, Tortoise (Subversion), Git and SQL Server.